<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ecmascript on A Place for Poor Examples</title>
    <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/ecmascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ecmascript on A Place for Poor Examples</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/ecmascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Performance Improvement via node 4 to node 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20161109-performance-improvement-via-babel-tranpilation-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20161109-performance-improvement-via-babel-tranpilation-removal/</guid>
      <description>My team at work recently upgraded our codebase to use to node 6.9, as node 6 has recently gone to LTS.
In the picture below, the 1st line is the upgrade from node 4 to node 6, and the corresponding flattening of memory usage vs. load.
The 2nd line is our removal of redis connection queueing in the application.
All of all, the memory consumption of our application is now averaging around 150MB, down from a high of 1GB!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node 4 and Babel 6 in Harmony</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20160116-node-4-and-babel-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20160116-node-4-and-babel-6/</guid>
      <description>Pun in title intentional I upgraded a heap of projects I was working on to node 4.2.3 and babel 6.
As I did a quick and dirty upgrade, I kept thinking to myself: doesn&amp;rsquo;t node 4/5 have pretty good support for es6/2015?
As I was looking around the internet for Hello Kitty Formalwear babel 6 upgrade tips, I came across this package which read my mind.
So if you&amp;rsquo;re a node 4/5 user, by doing this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to upgrading from Babel 5 =&gt; 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20151231-for-real-upgrade-babel-5-to-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20151231-for-real-upgrade-babel-5-to-6/</guid>
      <description>Because it&amp;rsquo;s changed since October There have been a bunch of guides on upgrading to babel 5.
Even those written in the last two months are already out of date. Babel moves annoyingly fast.
Please note: this is up to date as of 6.3.13. As I write this, it might also be obsolete.
Skip babel-core and babel-loader. User babel-register. Due to some complaints about the various ways you could bootstrap babel into an app, there is now babel-register.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
