<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-binding on A Place for Poor Examples</title>
    <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/data-binding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-binding on A Place for Poor Examples</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/data-binding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Derby.js - The Ready() Function, and Adding Client-Side Scripts to your App</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20121017-derby-js-the-ready-function-and-client-side-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20121017-derby-js-the-ready-function-and-client-side-scripts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found a neat feature of derby dealing with the ready() function. I&amp;rsquo;ve been creating a derby app, and in my application I need to load up a client-side calendar. With a standard HTML web page this is straightforward thing to do. On the page you wanted the calendar, you would include the client js for the calendar, some code to load it, and that would be that. Derby introduced some complexity to this relatively simple task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derby.js - Starting out with Components; Creating a Twitter Bootstrap Input Component</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20120825-derby-js-starting-out-with-components-creating-a-twitter-bootstrap-input-component/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20120825-derby-js-starting-out-with-components-creating-a-twitter-bootstrap-input-component/</guid>
      <description>In working with Twitter Bootstrap Forms, one of my favorite ways to lay out a form is using the Horizontal form layout. The layout requires a bit of css/html to get each of the form elements (the text boxes and what not) to play nicely. To add form elements to the horizontal form layout, you need the following html structure for each field:
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;control-group&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-- additional classes here to change state --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label class=&amp;#34;control-label&amp;#34;&amp;gt;INPUT_LABEL_TEXT_HERE&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;controls&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;input type=&amp;#34;text&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derby.js - Working with Views, Models, and Bindings</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20120807-derby-js-working-with-view-templates-models-and-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20120807-derby-js-working-with-view-templates-models-and-bindings/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post about derby, I talked a bit about how to create a model in derby and one rule you need to follow when creating models (the first two path segments should be an object).
I&amp;rsquo;m creating a test application to help me learn derby here. In the process of doing absolutely everything wrong to start I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a bit about how Derby binds to models. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re got some markup like this that you&amp;rsquo;d like to bind to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>