<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on A Place for Poor Examples</title>
    <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on A Place for Poor Examples</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 18:49:50 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breakdown; post-mortem of a process failure</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20210217-incident-remediation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 18:49:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20210217-incident-remediation/</guid>
      <description>I was reviewing an old incident review doc where I wrote up some of the high level learnings from the incident. Thought it was worth sharing, with the details omitted to protect the innocent.
Some backstory; we were trying to load test a component and ended up getting the load testing done at the last minute right before customer launch. The team had to work into the weekend to meet the customer deadline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure the Technical State of your Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20210110-measurable-technical-state-of-the-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 21:40:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20210110-measurable-technical-state-of-the-team/</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts on how you could evaluate the state of the systems your team owns.
One way to use this:
 Put some of these criteria on the Y axis Put the name of the components you own on the X. Give everything a score from 1 to 0. Either average the scores or sum them to figure out which components need the most love.  If all of these are the same for everything you own, it might make sense to skip that section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Backlog Health</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20200101-measuring-backlog-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:40:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20200101-measuring-backlog-health/</guid>
      <description>Backlog Grooming Some thoughts on how you could evaluate the state of your backlog.
Small, well groomed backlog
 Are the tickets in the backlog going to be actioned in the near term? If you deleted the tickets that aren&amp;rsquo;t in your near-term roadmap, how long would it take you to recreate it? Is the Backlog consistently growing or shrinking? Are the tickets all in a state to be actioned immediately, or do they need additional work?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
