<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical Excellence on A Place for Poor Examples</title>
    <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/technical-excellence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical Excellence on A Place for Poor Examples</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 03:10:07 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mattblair.co/tags/technical-excellence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crunch Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20230404-crunch-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 03:10:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20230404-crunch-time/</guid>
      <description>Crunch periods are a reality in many industries, and sometimes they are necessary to meet an immovable deadline. However, working under high-pressure situations for an extended period can lead to burnout, and it&amp;rsquo;s essential to provide support for the team after the crunch is over. In this blog post, we will discuss different approaches for formalized recovery time after a crunch period.
Ask team members what would make them feel valued One approach is to ask team members what would make them feel valued after the crunch period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Between Tech Stacks</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20230302-changing-stacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 17:31:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20230302-changing-stacks/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to software engineering roles, experience in the tech stack you&amp;rsquo;re going to be working in is valuable but not specifically required. A good engineer can ramp up and learn new stacks. However, someone experienced in the tech stack can contribute quickly to key development initiatives, while also bringing outside experience using the stack.
But which tech stacks are easier to move between, and which ones are the hardest?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Technical Excellence in your Organization</title>
      <link>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20230221-technical-excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 17:31:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mattblair.co/blog/20230221-technical-excellence/</guid>
      <description>I was speaking to a friend who works at a startup with a team of around 14 engineers. 80% of them are mid level engineers with 3-4 years of experience. They all work in product squads covering specific areas.
These have lost momentum in the development and they are seeing 2 key problems:
 The teams lacks direction on where to focus their energy and prefer tackling small issues as they don&amp;rsquo;t have a vision as to what impactful engineering initiatives to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
